Irving Berlin Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Photographs (Box 516-517, 569, 575, Mapcase 3)
  - The sin of Pat Muldoon, scene pictures, 27 photographs; On envelope: Richard Adler (Box-folder 517/11)
  - Danny Kaye at piano with others (scene shot from unidentified film), 2 photographs (Box-folder 517/11)
  - Various unidentified shots, 19 photographs (Box-folder 517/12)
  - Farm house and trees, 2 photocopied photographs (Box-folder 517/12)
  - George M. Cohan photograph with dedication to Irving Berlin from Agnes Cohan (Box 575)
  - Interior of Music Box Theatre, 1982, 2 photographs; Autographed by Michael Heller (Box 575)
  - Photographs of artwork for Irving Berlin from "Sam" Irving Hoffman, 2 photographs (Box 575)
  - Hespers Club group photograph, circa 1910 (Mapcase-drawer 3/6)
  - Irving Berlin at the White House with Richard Nixon, May 24, 1973, 1 copy autographed, Nixon (Mapcase-drawer 3/6)
  - Victor Herbert, headshot (Mapcase-drawer 3/6)
  - Unidentified female, headshot (Mapcase-drawer 3/6)
- Awards and Tributes (Box 538-541, 567, 601)
  - ASCAP awards (2) for Always: "Among the most performed country songs of 1983" (Box 538)
  - ASCAP award for White Christmas: "Among the most performed ASCAP standards 1973-1983" (Box 538)
  - ASCAP award for There's no business like show business: "Among the most performed ASCAP standards 1974-1984" (Box 539)
  - ASCAP award for White Christmas: "Among the most performed in feature film classics on television, 1974" (Box 539)
  - ASCAP award for writer of There's no business like show business: "Among the most performed ASCAP standards 1976-1986" (Box 539)
  - ASCAP award for publisher of There's no business like show business: "Among the most performed ASCAP standards 1976-1986" (Box 539)
  - Academy of motion picture arts and sciences nominations, 1942, 1946 (Box-folder 540/1)
  - Awards and tributes: miscellaneous, 1942-1974 (Box-folder 540/2)
  - Program from Boy Scouts tribute luncheon for Ellin Berlin, Silver Fawn Award, April 15, 1975 (Box-folder 540/3)
  - Clearfield High School yearbook tribute to Irving Berlin, 1945 (Box 541)
  - Souvenir album for Irving Berlin's 99th birthday from The Friends of the Foundation for New American Music at Henry Mancini's home, 1987 May 11 (Box 541)
  - ASCAP award (oversize) for publisher of God Bless America: "Among the most performed ASCAP standards 1978-1988" (Box 567)
  - ASCAP award (oversize) for writer of God Bless America: "Among the most performed ASCAP standards 1978-1988" (Box 567)
  - ASCAP award: America's songwriting genius; May 11, 1968" (Box 601)
- Original Artwork (Box 571-574, 581-582, 584)
  - Pencil sketches on cover of bulletin of Cazenovia Junior College (oversize), (believed to be in Irving Berlin’s hand) (Box 571)
  - Photographed reproductions of original paintings (oversize), (1 of 4); 25 items (Box 571)
  - Photographed reproductions of original paintings (oversize), (2 of 4); 30 items (Box 572)
  - Photographed reproductions of original paintings (oversize), (3 of 4); 50 items (Box 573)
  - Photographed reproductions of original paintings (oversize), (4 of 4); 27 items (Box 574)
  - Negatives of holographed reproductions of original paintings, (1 of 2) (Box 581)
  - Negatives of holographed reproductions of original paintings, (2 of 2) (Box 582)
  - Artwork by others (Box 584)
- Realia (Box 542, 568, 576, 583, 599-602)
  - Stationery/ashtray set; letter opener (Box 542)
  - Flag that flew over the Capitol on Irving Berlin's 100th birthday (Box 568)
  - Wooden engraving of Always (oversize) (Box 576)
  - Ornamental keepsake box and yarmulke (Box 583)
  - Notepad; wallets; calligraphy pen (Box 602)
  - Address and telephone books (Box-folder 599/1-3, 600/1-4)
  - Ellin Berlin calendars, 1973-1984 (Box-folder 599/4)
  - Log of household expenses and telephone calls, 1946-1949 (Box-folder 599/5)
  - Irving Berlin and Ellin Berlin notebooks (Box-folder 599/6)
  - Inventory of household items, 1940-1948 (Box-folder 600/5)
  - Log of household expenses, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 600/6)
  - Stamps (Box 601)
- Non-Berlin Materials (Box 586-593)
  Music, lyrics and screenplays by other composers.
  - Music by other composers
    - Baer, Abel (Box-folder 586/1)
      - It's no diff'rent now, Manuscript piano-vocal score; [3] p.
    - Carter, Benny (Box-folder 586/1)
      - Poor simple Simon, Manuscript lead sheet; [1] p.
    - Ciemgala, Arv (Box-folder 586/1)
      - Boston trieste, Manuscript piano score; [2] p.
      - Broadway Peggy, Manuscript piano score; [2] p.
      - Dzives prieks, Manuscript piano score; [2] p.
      - Laiks ir nauda! (Time is money), Manuscript piano score; [2] p.
      - Niceo, Manuscript piano score; [2] p.
      - Tango, Manuscript piano score; [2] p.
    - Clement, Mark (Box-folder 586/1)
      - I'm waiting, Manuscript score; 9 p.
    - Dreyer, David (Box-folder 586/2)
      - Keep your head above water, Photocopy of manuscript piano-vocal score; 3 p.
    - Driggs, Collins H. (Box-folder 586/2)
      - Ev'ry Tom, Dick and Harry's called John, Manuscript lead sheet; [2] p.
    - Hein, Silvio (Box-folder 586/2)
      - It's a wonderful spot, Manuscript piano-vocal score; 4 p.
    - Jenkins, Gordon (Box-folder 586/2)
      - Indian-giver, Manuscript piano-vocal score; [5] p.
    - Johnson, Don & Larry Harding (Box-folder 586/2)
      - They can never censor 'I love you', Manuscript lead sheet; [1] p.
    - Johnston, Arthur (lyrics by Sam Coslow) (Box-folder 586/2)
      - Parisian lover, Photocopy of manuscript parts; [11] items
    - Klaus, Kenneth (Box-folder 586/2)
      - La Soldadera, Printed piano score; 6 p.
    - Lafarge, Guy (Box-folder 586/2)
      - La Seine, Manuscript piano-vocal score; 3 p.; Laid in: manuscript piano score (refrain only); 2 p.
    - Lilley, Joseph J. (Box-folder 586/3)
      - Windshield wiper, Photocopy of manuscript piano-vocal score; 5 p.
    - Lombardo, Carmen (lyrics by Bob Russell) (Box-folder 586/3)
      - Back home for keeps, Sketches of manuscript scores (2 copies); 8 p. each; Manuscript lead sheet; [1] p.; Manuscript inserts; [12] leaves; Typescript lyric sheet; [1] p.
    - Luders, Gustav (Box-folder 586/3)
      - Untitled, Manuscript piano score; [5] p.
    - Lehar, Franz (Box-folder 586/3)
      - Die Rose, Manuscript piano-vocal score (no lyrics); [6] p.
    - McKee, Denny (Box-folder 586/3)
      - Our cottage by the sea, Manuscript lead sheet; [2] p.; Manuscript lead sheet (with manuscript lyrics); [3] p.
    - Meeks, Stanley & Alnia Hall (Box-folder 586/4)
      - I'm savin' my love, Photocopy of manuscript piano-vocal score; [3] p.; Typescript lyric sheets; [2] leaves
    - O'Neil, Danny (Box-folder 586/4)
      - Heartbroken, Manuscript piano-vocal score; [2] p.
    - Overton, Ruth Patillo (Box-folder 586/4)
      - As lonely they watched, Manuscript lead sheets (2 arrangements); [4] p.
    - Owens, Jack (Box-folder 586/4)
      - Put your little head on my shoulder, Manuscript lead sheet; [1] p.
    - Prospero, Fritz (Box-folder 586/4)
      - Once again (alternate lyric) "Welcome home boy of mine", Manuscript piano-vocal score; [3] p.; Laid in: letter (in ink), manuscript lyrics, (Fritz to George, 12/17/45 )
    - Ryan, Randy (Box-folder 586/4)
      - One more block, Manuscript lead sheet; [2] p.; Manuscript lyrics; [1] p.; Typescript lyric sheets (some with annotations); 8 leaves
    - Sands, Stephen (Box-folder 586/4)
      - You forgot to tell me that you love me, Typescript lyric sheets; [2] p.
    - Schmall, Rene Richard (Box-folder 586/5)
      - Die Spieluhr der Marquise, Manuscript parts; [10] p.
    - Sims, Alice D. (Box-folder 586/5)
      - You ain't what you used to be Susie, Manuscript lead sheet; [3] p.
    - Skylar, Sunny (Box-folder 586/5)
      - The victory waltz, Manuscript piano-vocal score; [2] p.
    - Slawson, David & Buck Ram (Box-folder 586/5)
      - Whistlin' in the breeze, Manuscript piano-vocal score; [4] p.
    - Steiner, Howard (Box-folder 586/5)
      - I heard a robin in the rain, Manuscript lead sheet (melody); [2] p.; Manuscript lyrics (pencil); [1] leaf; Typescript lyric sheets; [4] leaves
    - Symes, Marty, Dick Robertson and Frank Weldon (Box-folder 586/5)
      - Why did it have to end so soon, Sheet music
    - Thomas, Chandler (Box-folder 586/5)
      - Introduction and allegro (in two voices), Photocopy of manuscript lead sheet(?) (no lyrics); 7 p.
    - Thompson, Ken (Box-folder 586/5)
      - After all this time, Manuscript piano-vocal score; [4] p.
    - Tobias, Charles (Box-folder 586/6)
      - One little moment with you, Sketches; [6] p.
    - Vida, Pinky & Sunny Skylar (Box-folder 586/6)
      - At de beach, Manuscript lead sheet; [1] p.; Typescript lyric sheet (with annotations); 1 leaf
      - De big bass violin, Manuscript lead sheet; [1] p.; Typescript lyric sheets; [3] leaves
      - At de Kop kop baseball game, Manuscript lead sheet; [1] p.; Typescript lyric sheet; [1] p.
      - Never swat a fly on a dewberry pie, Manuscript lead sheet; [1] p.; Typescript lyric sheet; [1] p.
    - Winslow, Max (Box-folder 586/6)
      - Don't neglect me, Sketch; [2] p.; Typescript lyric sheets; [2] leaves
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 586/6)
      - Greensleeves, Sketch; [5] p.
    - Miscellaneous lyrics - non Berlin (Box-folder 586/7)
      - Photocopies of holograph lyric sheets (with autograph); 5 items
        - Bond, Carrie Jenkins
          - The end of a perfect day
        - Cohen, George M.
          - (Chorus of) Over there
        - Dietz, Howard
          - O give me something to remember you by
        - Hammerstein, Oscar
          - Old river
        - Mercer, Johnny
          - The windows of Paris
    - Printed music - non Berlin (Box-folder 587/1)
      - Sheet music; piano-vocal scores
        - Arlen, Harold
          - I never has seen snow
          - Two ladies in de shade of de banana tree
        - Braham
          - The Maguires
          - The MacIntyres
        - Brown, Francis
          - Our flag is there
        - Ellesworth, Bob
          - If I were Irving Berlin
        - Erdelyi, Joseph, Jr.
          - The star-spangled banner III
        - Foster, Stephen
          - Old dog tray
        - Francis, W.T.
          - The life of love
        - Goetz & Osbourne
          - Take me back to the garden of love
        - Hughes & Heyward
          - Freedom train
        - Izzo, Frankie
          - Ball and chain
          - Big black clouds
          - Chicken in the pot
          - Fortune all in snow
          - Kiss me now
          - Isle of joy
          - Moonlight paradise
          - Please don't shoot the 'Rover' (up to the moon for clover)
        - Jones, Clarence
          - Long lead on
        - Knight, Vic
          - Just a stow away
        - Macau, Miguel A.
          - Los poemas musicales
        - Roberts & Fisher
          - Good, good, good (That's you - that's you)
          - I lost a sweetheart
        - Rodgers, Richard
          - On your toes
        - Scherman, Robert
          - The daughter of Mrs. O'Dare
        - Tobias, Charles, Al Lewis & Harry Tobias
          - I've got the situation well in hand
        - Wilson, Sandy
          - I could be happy with you
          - It's never too late to fall in love
        - Wheeler, Kay
          - Strollin' along with you
      - Printed parts (Box-folder 587/2)
        - Kahn, Gus & Ted Fiorito
          - I never knew
        - Jolson, Al, Louis Silver & Grant Clarke
          - Mother of mine, I still have you
      - Miscellaneous titles (Box-folder 587/3)
        - Armed forces song folio, 1954 Sep. - Nov.
        - Beethoven
          - Rondino in G
          - Rondo in C
        - Cohan, George M.
          - The bell of the barbers' ball
        - Glover, Stephen
          - Fort Sumter grand march
        - Liszt
          - Dream of love (Liebestraum No. 3)
        - Mozart
          - Concerto in d minor
        - National melodies (series)
        - Key, Francis Scott
          - The star spangled banner
        - Covert, B.
          - Sword of Bunker Hill
        - Robinson, Russell
          - He's coming home on the eight o'clock train
        - Strauss
          - Spialek, The Danube
        - Wenzel, Charles
          - Etude for violincello
        - Wilson, William
          - The drum grandmarch
          - Zouaves quickstep
        - Winterbottom, Frank
          - Frank, Charlie is my darling, 2 copies: solo bassoon and piano; solo bassoon parts
  - Non-Berlin scripts/screenplays
    - Typescript/carbon copy scripts
      - Ainslee, Marian & Guy Endore (Box-folder 588/1)
        - Change partners, Carbon copy; 11 p.
      - Andrews, Robert (Box-folder 588/1)
        - The gift of God, Mimeograph copy of script; 158 p.
      - Andrews, Robert & Barry Trivers (Box-folder 588/1)
        - Gilded lady, Carbon copy; 100 p.
      - Atteridge, Harold (Box-folder 588/1)
        - Marx brothers (scenarios), Carbon copy; 10 p.
      - Beaton, Cecil (Box-folder 588/2)
        - (Untitled), Carbon copy with annotations; 78 p.
      - Bergman, Henry (Box-folder 588/2)
        - Calling a bluff, Typed script; [3] p.
      - Blake, Jr., Katherine (half sister of Ellin Berlin) (Box-folder 588/2)
        - The secret of Pan's doorway, Typed script; [10] p.
      - Caesar, Arthur (Box-folder 588/2)
        - A maker of images, Carbon copy; 14 p.
      - Delf, Harry (Box-folder 588/2)
        - Ring around Rosie, Typed script; 55 p.
      - Dolan, Robert Emmet (Box-folder 588/2)
        - Bring on the girls, Carbon copy; [60] p.
      - Davis, Eddie (Box-folder 588/2)
        - Not tonight, Josephine, Carbon copy; [118] p.
      - Ferber, Edna (Box-folder 589/1)
        - Showboat (continuity), Carbon copy of synopsis; 8 p.; At top: Elsa Neuberger, September 6, 1928
      - Fields, Herbert & Dorothy (Box-folder 589/1)
        - The works, Typed script (first draft); [88] p.
      - Freedman, Charles (Box-folder 589/1)
        - At the turnstile, Typed script; 10 p.
      - Geto, Pfc. Alfred D. (Box-folder 589/1)
        - Pack up your troubles, Mimeograph copy of script; 16 p.
      - Glickman, Will & Joseph Stein (Box-folder 589/1)
        - Mrs. Gibbon's boys, Carbon copy of script; [130] p.
      - Grashin, Mauri (Box-folder 589/1)
        - Two members of the bar, Carbon copy of lyrics; [5] p.
      - Grey, Elizabeth (Box-folder 589/1)
        - A night at Goldman's, Carbon copy of synopsis; 10 p.
      - Hattan, Frederick & Fanny (Box-folder 589/2)
        - Upstairs and down, Typed script; [87] p.
      - Hecht, Ben (Box-folder 589/2)
        - We will never die, Mimeograph copy of script; [46] p.
      - Herbert, F. Hugh (Box-folder 589/2)
        - Margie, Mimeograph copy of script; 152 p.
      - Holm, John Cecil (Box-folder 589/2)
        - One in a million, Typed script; 9 p.
      - Kasznar, Kurt (Box-folder 590/1)
        - First cousins, Mimeograph copy of script; 18 p.
      - Keaney, Ned Joyce (Box-folder 590/1)
        - The crown jewels, Carbon copy of script; 8 p.
      - Knoblock, Edward (Box-folder 590/1)
        - Scenario for South American musical play, Carbon copy of synopsis; [41] p.
      - Lagman, John H. (Box-folder 590/1)
        - Society, Photocopy of storyline; 7 p.
      - Lerner, Alan Jay (Box-folder 590/1)
        - Music! Music!, Mimeograph copy of script; [101] p.
      - Lowrey, Edward Wilburn (Box-folder 590/1)
        - Oh you doctor!, Typed script; 100 p.
      - Miller, Alice Duer (Box-folder 590/2)
        - The gift of groom, Carbon copy of story; [74] p.
      - Morris, Richard (Box-folder 590/2)
        - The unsinkable Mrs. Brown, Mimeograph copy of script; [102] p.
      - Neiman, Irving Gaynor, Pvt. (Box-folder 591/1)
        - Button your lip, Mimeograph copy of script; 19 p.
      - Nelson, Ralph; Aviation cadet (Box-folder 591/1)
        - Mail call, Mimeograph copy of script; 15 p.
      - Odea, John G., Pfc. (Box-folder 591/1)
        - Where e're we go, Mimeograph copy of script; 18 p.
      - Pemberton, Murdock (Box-folder 591/1)
        - Just my luck, Carbon copy storyline; 2 p.
        - One thousand years from today, Typed script; 9 p.; Laid in: Typescript letter from Pemberton to Irving Berlin; Carbon copy of storyline and script; 9 p.
      - Rinehart, Mary Roberts & Avery Hoewood (Box-folder 591/1)
        - Seven days, Carbon copy of script; [174] p.; Carbon copy of script; [185] p.
      - Shaw, Irwin (Box-folder 591/2)
        - Big game, Mimeograph copy of script; [134] p.
      - Smith, H.B. (Box-folder 591/2)
        - Round the clock, Typed scenario; 23 p.
      - Thompson, Harlan (Box-folder 591/2)
        - High hat, Act I, Carbon copy script; 87 p.
        - High hat, Act II, Carbon copy script; 42 p.
      - Wells, William K. (Box-folder 591/2)
        - Heading for Broadway, Carbon copy of script; 96 p.
    - Typescript/carbon copy scripts/screenplays - unidentified authors
      - Hawthorne of the USA, Carbon copies of scripts (4 folders); [27], [39], [22], [18] p. (Box-folder 592/1)
      - The magic city, Mimeograph copy of script; 160 p. (Box-folder 592/1)
      - Soldier show?, Carbon copies of typed script; [104] p. (Box-folder 592/2)
      - The song of the pioneer, Ditto copy of script (brown folder); 33 p. (Box-folder 592/2)
      - Stay away, Joe, Typescript synopsis, 3 p. (Box-folder 592/3)
      - Swinging the ring, Carbon copy; 11 p. (Box-folder 592/3)
      - Unidentified: "A political satire...", Typed script; 40 p. (Box-folder 592/3)
      - Unidentified, Typescript list of scenes (2 different); 2 p. each (Box-folder 592/3)
      - Unidentified, Carbon copies; p. 3, 4, 11-16 (Box-folder 592/3)
      - Unidentified: critic's review of play (National Anthem by Hartley Manners), Carbon copies; 4 p. (Box-folder 592/3)
    - Miscellaneous non-Berlin writings (Box-folder 593/1)
    - Miscellaneous non-Berlin printed matter (Box-folder 593/2)